[Music]
welcome to the akshar group in this
video all the information about trade
credit insurance is given this includes
important information related to
insurance like benefits available
feedback enrollment feedback as well as
the process to contact our office
the terms and conditions of the policy
are included read it carefully
let us further know what is trade credit
insurance
trade credit insurance is a type of
business insurance designed to protect
account receivables of a firm which may
get impacted due to non-payment or
defaults by the debtors or buyers one
such reason for buyers making defaults
in payments are commercial risk
protracted default plus insolvency or
political risk such risk may be beyond
the control of businesses or individuals
however protecting the business from
risks such as non-payment delay in
payment unknown buyer or unknown
geographies are vital to expanding the
business many national and private
insurance companies in india offer trade
credit insurance it helps business
owners recover from losses due to
customer defaults and in turn increases
business profits improves cash flow
increase sales and reduces unexpected
customer bankruptcy risks it also
protects the exporters from any loss
incurred due to political event
happening in the bias country because of
which bar is unable to make payment to
seller why should you buy trade credit
insurance as a result of globalization
business opportunities have increased
and companies are facing increasingly
complex requirements in terms of trade
receivables management trade credit
insurance is a tool that helps companies
expand businesses with peace of mind
trade credit protects insurance
companies from defaults by customers it
covers the sales of companies on credit
to its buyers against the risk of loss
due to non-payment bankruptcy and
political risk credit insurance plays an
important role in the business cycle of
any company by protecting the profit
cash flow sales growth balance street
and customer base of the company it can
greatly help in the growth of sales by
allowing safe growth of new buyers new
markets and credit given to the buyer
what are trade credit insurance covers
trade credit insurance covers two types
of risks commercial and political risks
commercial risk insolvency or bankruptcy
of the buyer protracted default willful
default or non-payment by buyer
political risk
general moratorium upon payment by the
government of the buyer's country
cancellation of import license political
events economic difficulties legislative
or administrative measures preventing
payments
military revolution riot or rebellion
non-payment by government buyer
government's decision to stop the
demonstration
how does trade credit insurance work let
us understand how trade credit insurance
works so that you can get timely
benefits when needed the biggest setback
in the functioning of any business be it
small medium or large is the financial
loss which can happen due to various
reasons there may be times when you have
sold a product or service to a customer
or group of customers and unfortunately
the payment gets dark if this amount
becomes large it can also lead to the
closure of the business
a trade credit insurance helps in
managing such situations by providing
the unpaid amount by the customer
this payment is made in a fixed
percentage and not 75 to 100 percent of
it as should be pre-specified in the
policy document
guidelines trade credit insurance new
trade credit guidelines allow licensed
banks and financial institutions to buy
credit insurance policy this change will
facilitate banks and financial
institutions to mitigate country risk
open up access to new markets and manage
non-payment risk associated with trade
financing portfolio
micro and small enterprises can now buy
a trade credit policy to cover a single
buyer this will enable general insurance
companies to offer single buyer credit
insurance cover to smes and msmes
considering the evolving risk needs of
these sectors revised indemnity for
trade credit insurance a trade credit
policy shall specify the indemnity limit
being offered and the maximum limit that
may be offered shall be clearly
indicated in the product filled with the
authority
irdai allows covers for projects with
tenure of more than six months the scope
of the cover has been widened to include
projects with tenure exceeding six
months under the policy irdai allows
coverage for rejection of material in
case of goods customized to a buyer
coverage can be extended for non-payment
risk due to rejection by the buyer
before shipment where the goods are
manufactured or being manufactured
exclusively as per the requirements of
the buyer and cannot be sold elsewhere
the buyer after delivery subject to
continuous of the contract eligibility
criteria any company that has
receivables on its balance sheet is
likely to suffer losses from a
customer's inability or failure to pay
such companies can enroll for a trade
credit insurance policy exclusions under
credit insurance
not all situations are covered by credit
insurance also known as exclusion any
problems caused to the business due to
the following reasons are not included
no nuclear exposure due to radioactive
substances customer dispute with the
buyer which may result in withholding of
payment in full or in part by the buyer
any interest amount that occurs after
the original due payment date amount
outstanding by any government entity
which cannot be declared insolvent
currency volatility reverse factoring
policies pre-shipment risk turnover
declaration within 15 days from the end
of quarterly reporting period of gross
invoice value of eligible shipment to
which it relates
stop shipment you must stop all
shipments or sales to that particular
buyer that have been due for more than
60 days you will report monthly to the
insurer for accounts receivable for any
buyer that exceeds 30 days due you shall
report to the insurer at least 15 days
prior to the expiry of the policy all
accounts receivable for the insured of
the buyer under the policy trade credit
insurance claim process many national
and private insurance companies in india
offer trade credit insurance policies in
india however internal systems and
processes may be different for different
companies let us look at some general
guidelines regarding the processing or
settlement of claims in india must
submit written proof of damages within
12 months after the end of the waiting
period or within 30 days as requested by
the insurance company
usually in case of bankruptcy of the
buyer documentation required at the time
of claim
duly signed and stamped notification of
overdue account or claim form clear and
legible invoice copies
statement of account noa and soa dates
must be the same balance confirmation
proof of delivery purchase order sales
contract debit or credit note copies if
there are any
copy of communication with the debtor
following up for payment any other
document as specified by the insurers
note all the above documents are not
mandatory and can be discussed on cases
to case basis
if you have any questions or need any
additional information the team letters
will be happy to assist you with all
matters related to your insurance
benefits to know more about this scheme
or to buy it please contact akshar group
please do not delay in taking this
decision contact us today thank you